Now, let's learn about searching and not in singly linked list.
For that, we need to create a search, not method.
This method will go and search for the specific key.
If the key is included in and found inside the link, at least it will return one.
Otherwise, it will return minus one.
For that, we have created it's returning type as A..
OK.
So this search no method took into perimeter struck, not had which the head it a forensic in the heart
of the head.
Where is the head and and the cue that we are searching for?
So we create struct no damp equal to had.
This is the dinner party.
Had it's equal to the head and we are pointing over to the head.
It's a note that contains 18 OK and the last note is one one nine.
That the next to it is pointing to, then not OK.
So the difference is that pointing to now we start.
While timc does not equal to null, then go and execute them equal time of the next.
So temp is equal to the reference of their next.
OK, if temp of data equal equal to the key, then return what we are comparing one one nine, which
is the key that we have inserted and passed in the 30 meter we are searching for one, one, nine and
six six.
Is that data that it's contained in the middle?
Not so.
One one nine is not equal to six six.
It continues the loop.
So.
Them will move to the next preference and then keep the temp of data is equal equal to the key?
Yes.
So one one nine is equal to the reference is equal to the data of the last not.
OK, so here we have found that that temp of data equal the key.
So the temporary value that we are searching for, which is one one nine representing the key is they
are equal, so return one.
This is the key of.
And this is the algorithm of searching for it, not in singly linked list.
Now let's consider another example if the temperature the key that we are searching for is 200.
So at the start, again, by creating temp at the head and start moving, start comparing numbers to
100 equal equal to 60 66.
Now it moves again.
And to the last not one one nine is not equal to 200, so they are not the equal.
And the last one is pointing to the end of the linked list, which is the reference in the next reference,
it's equal turn and then all pointing to null.
Therefore, we have reached the linked list without finding the corresponding note or the corresponding
key.
Therefore, it will return minus one.
What about time complexity?
So the algorithm of searching is not in singly linked list in the best case of one.
So if we have searching for the first, not, consider this linked list.
If we are searching for 18, then it's all of one because it's the first not.
But consider the case of that.
We have taken example one one nine.
We need to search all the elements of the linked list to find the last one.
OK.
And that is the last one.
So the worst case scenario is of searching for the last.
No.
OK.
This is the time complexity of searching and not in single place.
To sea in Java.
How we can make we create into the left class.
Not it.
It's of a genetic type of data data stored in each not list.
And then we create pointed to the next not interlinked list called next and not the class constructor
we are creating and constructing.
And not that out of time element E!
By the way, if you need to learn more about Java and deeply go in Java, you can go with the courses
that we have on Udemy and you get the free Capone to continue learning and you can message us and contact
us and we send you the coupons free in order to allow you learn Java.
And in the mastering way to the right, we have a linked list class this link.
At least it contains a public and search is the same search the the method that we have created before
it took element and search for that.
If had equal call to null, there is no reference.
There is no nonce.
Otherwise, it will make a while loop and start searching for the temp, the data equal to element.
Otherwise, it will return in the index.
If not included, it will return minus the.